<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <identifier>SuperSmashBrosUltimateExpandedSountrackVol.30</identifier>
  <scanner>Internet Archive Python library 4.1.0</scanner>
  <uploader>archive.intra@protonmail.com</uploader>
  <mediatype>data</mediatype>
  <collection>opensource</collection>
  <title>Super Smash Bros Ultimate Expanded Sountrack Vol. 30 Other</title>
  <publicdate>2024-06-29 23:30:45</publicdate>
  <addeddate>2024-06-29 23:30:45</addeddate>
  <curation>[curator]validator@archive.org[/curator][date]20240629233611[/date][comment]checked for malware[/comment]</curation>
  <creator>Nintendo</creator>
  <description>Vol. 30: Others ♪ Super Smash Bros. Ultimate Expanded Soundtrack&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Vol. 30 ♪ Dairantou Smash Bros. Special Expanded Soundtrack&lt;br /&gt;大乱闘スマッシュブラザーズ SPECIAL オリジナル・サウンドトラック&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Release Date&lt;br /&gt;December 07, 2018&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Artists&lt;br /&gt;Akito Nakatsuka, Asuka Ito, Hajime Wakai, Hideaki Shimizu, Hideki Kanazashi, Hiroaki Suga, Hirokazu Ando, Hirokazu Tanaka, Keigo Ozaki, Kenichi Okuma, Kenji Ito, Kenji Yamamoto, Kenta Nagata, Kentaro Ishizaka, Kiyoshi Hazemoto, Kohei Matsuoka, Koichi Kyuma, Koji Hayama, Koji Kondo, Kristofer Maddigan, Maki Kirioka, Manabu Namiki, Masafumi Takada, Masato Coda, Masato Kouda, Masaya Kuzume, Minako Hamano, Motoi Sakuraba, Noriyuki Iwadare, Riyu Tamura, Ryo Watanabe, Shogo Sakai, Shohei Tsuchiya, Soyo Oka, Takeshi Yanagawa, Tetsuya Shibata, Toby Fox, Toru Minegishi, Toshiyuki Sudo, Tsukasa Masuko, Yoko Shimomura, Yoshihito Yano, Yoshito Sekigawa, Yuichi Ozaki, Yuka Tsujiyoko, Yukio Kaneoka, Yusuke Takahama, Yuzo Koshiro&lt;br /&gt;Classification    Game Soundtrack - GameRip&lt;br /&gt;Games&lt;br /&gt;1080° Snowboarding, Art Academy, Assassin's Creed II, Balloon Fight, Baten Kaitos Origins, Big Brain Academy, Brain Age 2: More Training in Minutes a Day!, Brain Age: Train Your Brain in Minutes a Day!, Captain Rainbow, Clu Clu Land, Code Name: S.T.E.A.M., Culdcept 3DS, Culdcept Revolt, Cuphead, Devil May Cry, Devil World, Dillon's Dead-Heat Breakers, Dillon's Rolling Western: The Last Ranger, Donkey Kong Jr., Duck Hunt, Electroplankton, Ever Oasis, Excite Truck, Excitebike, Fallout 4, Famicom Grand Prix II: 3D Hot Rally, Fossil Fighters: Frontier, Freakyforms: Your Creations, Alive!, Glory of Heracles, Golden Sun: Dark Dawn, Golden Sun: The Lost Age, Ice Climber, Jam with the Band, Joy Mech Fight, Mach Rider, Mario + Rabbids Kingdom Battle, Miitopia, Monster Hunter, Monster Hunter 4, NES Remix 2, Nintendo Badge Arcade, Nintendo Land, Nintendogs, No More Heroes, Panel de Pon, Personal Trainer: Cooking, Pilotwings, Pilotwings Resort, Punch-Out!!, Rhythm Heaven, Rhythm Heaven Fever, Rhythm Heaven Megamix, Sakura Samurai: Art of the Sword, Shantae: Half-Genie Hero, Shin Onigashima, Snipperclips, Soma Bringer, Steel Diver: Sub Wars, StreetPass Mii Plaza, Stretchmo, Style Savvy: Styling Star, Style Savvy: Trendsetters, Super Bomberman R, Super Mario Bros. 3, Super Mario RPG, Super Smash Bros. Brawl, Super Smash Bros. for Nintendo 3DS and Wii U, Super Smash Bros. Melee, Super Smash Bros. Ultimate, Tales of Symphonia, Tank Troopers, Tetris, The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim, The Mysterious Murasame Castle, The Wonderful 101, Tomodachi Collection, Tomodachi Life, Undertale, Virtua Fighter 2, Wii Party U, Wii Play, Wii Sports, Wii Sports Club, Wii Sports Resort, Wrecking Crew&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ver 12.0 Update FLAC released on June 29th, 2021&lt;br /&gt;Challenger Pack 10&lt;br /&gt;Fighter: Kazuya&lt;br /&gt;Stage: Mishima Dojo&lt;br /&gt;Music: Tekken music&lt;br /&gt;Spirits: Tekken DLC Spirit Board&lt;br /&gt;Lloyd's Wig + Outfit&lt;br /&gt;Dragonborn's Helm + Armor&lt;br /&gt;Dante's Wig + Outfit&lt;br /&gt;Shantae's Wig + Outfit + Burning Town&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;At this patch the numbers are the following:&lt;br /&gt;Covers, don't know who made them but thank you =)&lt;br /&gt;Disc 1 106 songs&lt;br /&gt;Disc 2 80 songs&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ver 13.0.0 released on October 18th, 2021&lt;br /&gt;This is Sora's update&lt;br /&gt;Octoling Wig&lt;br /&gt;Judd Wig&lt;br /&gt;Doom Slayer Helmet + Armor&lt;br /&gt;Players who have save data for Kingdom Hearts Melody of Memory on their Nintendo Switch will be gifted the Dearly Beloved -Swing Version- music track.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Although it isn't available in-game, the track "At Doom's Gate" from Doom (2016) is used throughout the trailer&lt;br /&gt;DOOM Original Game Soundtrack Track 3&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;13.0.1 various amiibo support&lt;br /&gt;13.0.2 Sora's amiibo support&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;At the end of this patch there are&lt;br /&gt;Disc 1 107 songs&lt;br /&gt;Disc 2 93 songs&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;More info at:&lt;br /&gt;https://www.ssbwiki.com/List_of_updates_(SSBU)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;https://archive.org/details/super-smash-bros.-ultimate-expanded-soundtrack</description>
  <subject>smash bros ultimate soundtrack audio flac ost vol 30 volume</subject>
</metadata>
