<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <identifier>Cory_Doctorow_Podcast_233</identifier>
  <uploader>doctorow@craphound.com</uploader>
  <addeddate>2012-08-14 09:37:04</addeddate>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <title>Doubling Down on DRM</title>
  <description>Here's a podcast of my recent &lt;em&gt;Publishers Weekly&lt;/em&gt; column, &lt;a href="http://www.publishersweekly.com/pw/by-topic/columns-and-blogs/cory-doctorow/article/53544-doubling-down-on-drm.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;Doubling Down on DRM&lt;/a&gt;:

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I've just seen a letter sent to an author who has published books under Hachette's imprints in some territories and with Tor Books and its sister companies in other territories (Tor is part of Macmillan). The letter, signed by Hachette's U.K. CEO Ursula Mackenzie, explains to the author that Hachette has 'acquired exclusive publication rights in our territories from you in good faith,' but warns that in other territories, Tor's no-DRM policy 'will make it difficult for the rights granted to us to be properly protected.' Hachette's proposed solution: that the author insist Tor use DRM on these titles. 'We look forward to hearing what action you propose taking.'
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The letter also contains language that will apparently be included in future Hachette imprint contracts, language that would require authors to 'ensure that any of his or her licensees of rights in territories not licensed under this agreement' will use DRM.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It's hard to say what's more shocking to me: the temerity of Hachette to attempt to dictate terms to its rivals on the use of anti-customer technology, or the evidence-free insistence that DRM has some nexus with improving the commercial fortunes of writers and their publishers. Let's just say that Hachette has balls the size of Mars if it thinks it can dictate what other publishers do with titles in territories where it has no rights. take black American music's rock-n-roll rhythms without permission, but DJ Danger Mouse can't take the Beatles' melodies from the White Album to make the illegal hiphop classic The Grey Album.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Mastering by John Taylor Williams: wryneckstudio@gmail.com
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
John Taylor Williams is a audiovisual and multimedia producer based in Washington, DC and the co-host of the Living Proof Brew Cast. Hear him wax poetic over a pint or two of beer by visiting &lt;a href="http://livingproofbrewcast.com/" rel="nofollow"&gt;livingproofbrewcast.com&lt;/a&gt;. In his free time he makes "Beer Jewelry" and "Odd Musical Furniture." He often "meditates while reading cookbooks."  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
  <subject>sciencefiction;corydoctorow;podcast;publishing;drm;business</subject>
  <creator>Cory Doctorow</creator>
  <licenseurl>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licenseurl>
  <publicdate>2012-08-14 09:37:10</publicdate>
  <boxid>OL100020112</boxid>
  <backup_location>ia903905_33</backup_location>
  <collection>podcast_corydoctorow</collection>
  <collection>podcasts</collection>
  <external_metadata_update>2019-04-11T04:45:05Z</external_metadata_update>
  <collection>podcasts_miscellaneous</collection>
</metadata>
