<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <identifier>kid-icarus-uprising-original-soundtrack</identifier>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <collection>hifidelity_soundtracks</collection>
  <creator>Hirokazu Tanaka, Motoi Sakuraba, Yuzo Koshiro, Masafumi Takada, Noriyuki Iwadare, Takahiro Nishi, Yasunori Mitsuda, Natsumi Kameoka</creator>
  <date>2012-03-22</date>
  <description>&lt;b&gt;Title: &lt;/b&gt;Kid Icarus: Uprising&lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Alternate Title: &lt;/b&gt;新・光神話 パルテナの鏡 (Shin Hikari Shinwa Palutena no Kagami)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Platform: &lt;/b&gt;Nintendo 3DS&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Year of Release: &lt;/b&gt;2012&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Published by: &lt;/b&gt;Nintendo&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Developed by: &lt;/b&gt;Project Sora&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Soundtrack by: &lt;/b&gt;Hirokazu Tanaka, Motoi Sakuraba, Yuzo Koshiro, Masafumi Takada, Noriyuki Iwadare, Takahiro Nishi, Yasunori Mitsuda, Natsumi Kameoka&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Music History: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;Takahiro Nishi&lt;/i&gt; acted as the music director for the game, and the orchestral arrangements were handled by &lt;i&gt;Natsumi Kameoka and Yasunori Mistuda&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Natsumi Kameoka was responsible for taking specific pieces of music and arranging them into a complete track, then adjusting the speed of the track to fit into the game. Yasunori Mitsuda mentioned that the team created most of the soundtrack through live recordings which usually took at least seven recording sessions to complete and finalize, leading him to believe that this project was likely the largest-scale production of any video game score at the time.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;Hirokazu Tanaka&lt;/i&gt; composed the original tracks for &lt;i&gt;Kid Icarus&lt;/i&gt; on the Nintendo Entertainment System (the prequel to &lt;i&gt;Kid Icarus: Uprising&lt;/i&gt;), which some of his pieces were rearranged for this game. Composers &lt;i&gt;Motoi Sakuraba, Yuzo Koshiro, Masafumi Takada, Noriyuki Iwadare, Takahiro Nishi&lt;/i&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;Yasunori Mitsuda&lt;/i&gt; were many of the same artists who worked on the critically acclaimed &lt;i&gt;Super Smash Bros. Brawl&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
  <scanner>Internet Archive HTML5 Uploader 1.6.4</scanner>
  <subject>kid icarus</subject>
  <subject>Kid Icarus: Uprising</subject>
  <subject>nintendo</subject>
  <subject>soundtrack</subject>
  <subject>video game</subject>
  <subject>video game music</subject>
  <subject>3DS</subject>
  <subject>Nintendo 3DS</subject>
  <title>Kid Icarus: Uprising Original Soundtrack [Nintendo 3DS]</title>
  <uploader>jalenmy09@gmail.com</uploader>
  <publicdate>2022-01-08 05:09:52</publicdate>
  <addeddate>2022-01-08 05:09:52</addeddate>
  <curation>[curator]validator@archive.org[/curator][date]20220108055548[/date][comment]checked for malware[/comment]</curation>
  <year>2012</year>
  <notes>This is a 3-disc version of the soundtrack that was released on August 21st for Japanese Club Nintendo Members the same year.</notes>
  <collection>hifidelity</collection>
</metadata>
