<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <identifier>TheLionKingOriginalMotionPictureSoundtrack</identifier>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <collection>hifidelity_soundtracks</collection>
  <creator>Walt Disney Records</creator>
  <date>1994-05-31</date>
  <description>Disney storytelling magic meets the musical powers of 1992 Academy Award-winning lyricist Tim Rice, Grammy Award-winning writer and performer Elton John, and renowned composer Hans Zimmer in the original motion picture soundtrack for Walt Disney Pictures' animated masterpiece, &lt;i&gt;The Lion King&lt;/i&gt;. Weaving the rhythms and sounds of Africa into its captivating songs and evocative score, this soundtrack creates a sweeping musical landscape you'll never forget.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Tracks:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Circle of Life (Performed by Carmen Twillie)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I Just Can't Wait to Be King (Performed by Jason Weaver with Rowan Atkinson and Laura Williams)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Be Prepared (Performed by Jeremy Irons with Whoopi Goldberg, Cheech Marin, and Jim Cummings)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Hakuna Matata (Performed by Nathan Lane and Ernie Sabella with Jason Weaver and Joseph Williams)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Can You Feel the Love Tonight (Performed by Joseph Williams and Sally Dworsky with Nathan Lane, Ernie Sabella, and Kristle Edwards)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;This Land (instrumental)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;...To Die For (instrumental)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Under the Stars (instrumental)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;King of Pride Rock (instrumental)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Circle of Life (Performed by Elton John)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I Just Can't Wait to Be King (Performed by Elton John)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Can You Feel the Love Tonight" (end title) - Performed by Elton John&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
  <scanner>Internet Archive HTML5 Uploader 1.7.0</scanner>
  <subject>The Lion King</subject>
  <subject>Original Motion Picture Soundtrack</subject>
  <title>The Lion King (Original Motion Picture Soundtrack)</title>
  <uploader>cnix659@aol.com</uploader>
  <publicdate>2023-09-15 03:45:17</publicdate>
  <addeddate>2023-09-15 03:45:17</addeddate>
  <curation>[curator]validator@archive.org[/curator][date]20230915034535[/date][comment]checked for malware[/comment]</curation>
  <year>1994</year>
  <collection_added>hifidelity</collection_added>
  <collection>hifidelity</collection>
</metadata>
