<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <identifier>Cory_Doctorow_Podcast_458</identifier>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <collection>podcasts_miscellaneous</collection>
  <creator>Cory Doctorow</creator>
  <date>2023-12-17</date>
  <description>
&lt;p&gt;
This week on my podcast, I read my final &lt;em&gt;Medium&lt;/em&gt; column &lt;a href="https://pluralistic.net/2023/10/21/the-internets-original-sin/" rel="nofollow"&gt;
The internet's original sin&lt;/a&gt;, about the failure of trying to stretch copyright to cover every problem on the internet.

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Copyright is a regulation. It regulates the supply-chain of the entertainment industry. Copyright matters a lot to me, because I’m in the industry.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But unless you’re in the industry, it shouldn’t matter to you.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It’s fine to require a grasp of copyright among people who write, publish and distribute novels — but it’s bananas to require people who read novels to understand copyright.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And yet, here we are.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The test for whether copyright applies to you — for whether you are part of the entertainment industry’s supply chain — is whether you are making or dealing in copies of creative works. This test was once a very good one.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Back when every book had a printing press in its history, every record a record-pressing plant, every film a film-lab, “making or handling copies of creative works” was a pretty good test to determine whether someone was part of the entertainment industry. Even if it turned out they weren’t, the kind of person who has a record-pressing plant can afford to consult an expert to make sure they’re on the right side of the law.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
  <language>eng</language>
  <licenseurl>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</licenseurl>
  <scanner>Internet Archive HTML5 Uploader 1.7.0</scanner>
  <subject>Cory Doctorow</subject>
  <subject>podcasts</subject>
  <subject>copyfight</subject>
  <subject>internet</subject>
  <subject>internet regulation</subject>
  <title>The Internet's Original Sin</title>
  <uploader>doctorow@craphound.com</uploader>
  <publicdate>2023-12-17 19:37:33</publicdate>
  <addeddate>2023-12-17 19:37:33</addeddate>
  <curation>[curator]validator@archive.org[/curator][date]20231217193843[/date][comment]checked for malware[/comment]</curation>
  <collection>podcasts</collection>
</metadata>
