[SAME header]
[Attention signal]
This is a test of the Emergency Alert System.
This is only a test.
The message you are hearing is part of a nationwide, live code test
of Emergency Alert System capabilities.
This test message has been initiated-
-by national alert and warning authorities.
In coordination with Emergency Alert System participants including
broadcasts, cable, satellite, and wire line participants in your area.
Had this been an actual emergency, the attention signal you'd just heard
would have been followed by emergency information, news, or instructions.
This is only a test.
We now return you to regular programming.
[EOM]