<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <identifier>Cory_Doctorow_Podcast_224</identifier>
  <uploader>doctorow@craphound.com</uploader>
  <addeddate>2012-04-02 10:21:32</addeddate>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <collection>podcast_corydoctorow</collection>
  <title>A Whip to Beat Us With</title>
  <description>Here's a podcast of my last &lt;em&gt;Publishers Weekly&lt;/em&gt; column, &lt;a href="http://www.publishersweekly.com/pw/by-topic/columns-and-blogs/cory-doctorow/article/51292-cory-doctorow-a-whip-to-beat-us-with.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;A Whip to Beat Us With&lt;/a&gt;:

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jim C. Hines's e-books are marketed both through a big publisher and solo. The books that were re-priced by Amazon were his solo titles -- unagented, and unrepresented by a major publisher. As an individual, Jim has no leverage over Amazon. Not so Macmillan, which controls a much larger number of SKUs and has much more leverage. Macmillan made headlines during its tense standoff with Amazon in 2011 over e-book pricing, but the publisher was able to sway Amazon because it could make a credible threat that it might get up from the negotiating table and take all its books, too'and others might follow. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; But Macmillan's edge'its scale'is also its undoing. Every day, Macmillan sells more e-books that have been locked into Amazon's format. The millions of dollars that Amazon customers spend on Macmillan's DRM-locked e-books represent millions of dollars of e-books Macmillan customers lose if they wanted to follow Macmillan away from Amazon. Publishers believe DRM protects their books. But DRM has created a world where publishers who walk away from negotiations with a DRM vendor like Amazon leave their customers behind. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Not just Macmillan. Any publisher that sees a substantial portion of its income from DRM vendors becomes little more than a commodity supplier to those vendors. If Hachette or HarperCollins decided to bite the bullet and pull their titles from Amazon during a dispute, how many of their authors would stay with them, knowing that the world's largest bookseller and most popular e-book platform no longer carried their titles? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; To appreciate this vulnerability, just look at what happened in February with the Independent Publishers Group, a distributor that asked Amazon to hold the line on its discount. They weren't able to reach an agreement, and Amazon removed all IPG's e-books from the Kindle store. The day that happened, IPG sent out a communique describing the situation and asking its readers to avoid the Kindle store in future.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Mastering by John Taylor Williams: wryneckstudio@gmail.com
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
John Taylor Williams is a full-time self-employed audio engineer, producer, composer, and sound designer. In his free time, he makes beer, jewelry, odd musical instruments and furniture. He likes to meditate, to read and to cook.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
  <subject>publishing;drm;business;apple;ibooks;</subject>
  <creator>Cory Doctorow</creator>
  <licenseurl>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licenseurl>
  <publicdate>2012-04-02 10:21:38</publicdate>
  <boxid>OL100020112</boxid>
  <backup_location>ia903801_5</backup_location>
  <collection>podcasts</collection>
  <collection>podcasts_miscellaneous</collection>
</metadata>
