<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <identifier>SimCity2000MIDIMacOSSF</identifier>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <collection>folksoundomy_gamesoundtracks</collection>
  <creator>Maxis</creator>
  <date>1993</date>
  <description>&lt;pre&gt;SimCity 2000 MIDI Soundtrack - Mac OS Soundfont version&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Game: SimCity 2000 (DOS)&lt;br /&gt;Year: 1993&lt;br /&gt;Composer: Sue Karen&lt;br /&gt;Publisher: Maxis&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;----&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is a recording (originally FLAC, but available in multiple formats&lt;br /&gt;through the Internet Archive) of the SimCity 2000 MIDI soundtrack, using a&lt;br /&gt;custom soundfont created by Rich "Weeds" Nagel and Tom "Zarggg" Ditmars. The&lt;br /&gt;MIDI files are from the MS-DOS version and were edited to work with the new&lt;br /&gt;custom soundfont, and won't sound correctly unless played back using it. The&lt;br /&gt;soundfont is included in SC2KMac.zip.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I made small edits to two of the MIDI files. "Newspaper Segue" (10010.MID) and&lt;br /&gt;"Virtual Village" (10011.MID) both used two woodblock instrument channels&lt;br /&gt;which didn't correct using the Mac OS soundfont--in the Mac OS version itself&lt;br /&gt;these instruments aren't woodblocks. You can find these in "Edited&lt;br /&gt;tracks.zip". The originals are in "Unused tracks.zip" if you want to compare.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Aside from that edit, I also modified the order in which the tracks are&lt;br /&gt;played, and omitted one track (which is also in "Unused tracks.zip"): the&lt;br /&gt;"Repetition Rendition" actually has two versions in the DOS soundtrack, with&lt;br /&gt;different main instruments, but the Mac OS version doesn't have the alternate&lt;br /&gt;instrument so it would've been a duplicate. Tracks 16 and 17 are also shorter&lt;br /&gt;versions of previous tracks, but since they actually do play back in the game&lt;br /&gt;I've kept them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Also, a modified version of the original SimCity Classic background music is&lt;br /&gt;included as well, made to use this soundfont's instruments. In case you've&lt;br /&gt;wanted to hear what the original game's background music sounds like if it had&lt;br /&gt;been included in SimCity 2000.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I've ordered the tracks slightly differently from most releases. It starts&lt;br /&gt;with the main theme, then the longer tracks, then the shorter tracks/snippets,&lt;br /&gt;finally the unused track and the SimCity Classic theme.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;All tracks are in FLAC L8 (highest compression) and have 500ms affix/1500ms&lt;br /&gt;suffix silence.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;----&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Released by: dada78641, 2020-01-26&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Archive of this soundtrack:&lt;br /&gt;https://archive.org/details/SimCity2000MIDIMacOSSF&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Archive of the soundfont:&lt;br /&gt;https://archive.org/details/SC2KMac.zip&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The soundfont project was initiated on the Vogons forum:&lt;br /&gt;https://www.vogons.org/viewtopic.php?f=9&amp;t=22804&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The SC2KMac.zip file with the soundfont was posted there as well:&lt;br /&gt;https://www.vogons.org/viewtopic.php?p=192865#p192865&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
  <language>eng</language>
  <scanner>Internet Archive HTML5 Uploader 1.6.4</scanner>
  <subject>SimCity 2000</subject>
  <subject>Soundtrack</subject>
  <subject>OST</subject>
  <subject>FLAC</subject>
  <subject>Mac OS</subject>
  <subject>DOS</subject>
  <subject>MIDI</subject>
  <subject>General MIDI</subject>
  <subject>Soundfont</subject>
  <title>OST - SimCity 2000 (Mac OS Soundfont)</title>
  <uploader>michiel@thingmajig.org</uploader>
  <publicdate>2020-01-26 18:25:35</publicdate>
  <addeddate>2020-01-26 18:25:35</addeddate>
  <year>1993</year>
  <collection>folksoundomy</collection>
  <backup_location>ia907103_3</backup_location>
</metadata>
