<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <identifier>journey-soundtrack-2012</identifier>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <collection>hifidelity_soundtracks</collection>
  <creator>Austin Wintory</creator>
  <date>2012-04-10</date>
  <description>&lt;b&gt;Journey&lt;/b&gt; is an indie adventure game co-developed by Thatgamecompany and Santa Monica Studio, published by Sony Computer Entertainment, and directed by Jenova Chen. It was released for the PlayStation 3 via PlayStation Network in March 2012 and ported to PlayStation 4 in July 2015. It was later ported to Microsoft Windows in June 2019 and iOS in August 2019. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;The music in Journey&lt;/b&gt; was composed and orchestrated by Austin Wintory, who had previously worked with Thatgamecompany on the soundtrack for Flow. Wintory worked closely on the soundtrack with sound designer Steve Johnson, as well as the programming team, so the music would dynamically tie in to both the actions of the player and to sound effects caused by nearby game objects, and feel as if it were "unfolding in real time". Johnson felt having short pieces of music that looped without reacting to the player would be a "missed opportunity", and wanted to create music that changed while still containing a composed emotional arc. Jenova Chen met with Wintory at the start of the game's development to describe his vision for the project, and Wintory left the meeting and created the core of the main theme before he reached his car, and composed and recorded the main cello theme for the soundtrack that night. He continued to work on the soundtrack for the next three years in a collaboration with the development team; he would create a track, which the team would use while creating an area in the game, and Wintory would play the section while revising the music and then send it back. Wintory spent time experimenting and discarding many ideas; while the first track, "Nascence", came easily, the final track, "Apotheosis", went through several widely varied attempts</description>
  <language>eng</language>
  <scanner>Internet Archive HTML5 Uploader 1.6.4</scanner>
  <subject>Journey</subject>
  <subject>Austin Wintory</subject>
  <subject>Sony Computer Entertainment</subject>
  <subject>Thatgamecompany</subject>
  <subject>Santa Monica Studio</subject>
  <subject>Jenova Chen</subject>
  <subject>Playstation 3</subject>
  <subject>PS3</subject>
  <subject>Playstation music</subject>
  <subject>adventure game</subject>
  <subject>Robin Hunicke</subject>
  <subject>Playstation 4</subject>
  <subject>PS4</subject>
  <subject>game music</subject>
  <subject>game soundtrack</subject>
  <subject>game ost</subject>
  <subject>orchestrated music</subject>
  <subject>soundtrack score</subject>
  <title>Journey Soundtrack (2012)</title>
  <uploader>krsj1982@gmail.com</uploader>
  <publicdate>2021-04-15 21:08:01</publicdate>
  <addeddate>2021-04-15 21:08:01</addeddate>
  <curation>[curator]validator@archive.org[/curator][date]20210415210838[/date][comment]checked for malware[/comment]</curation>
  <collection>hifidelity</collection>
</metadata>
