<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <identifier>rudolph_misfit_toys_soundtrack</identifier>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <collection>hifidelity_soundtracks</collection>
  <creator>GoodTimes Entertainment, Chalkboard Music Inc.</creator>
  <date>2001-09-25</date>
  <description>&lt;div&gt;A full soundtrack sampler of songs from the beloved or despised 2001 CGI direct-to-video film, Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer &amp; The Island of Misfit Toys; the sequel to the 1964 Rankin/Bass classic.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Sampler includes seven original (yet forgettable) songs, the classic Rudolph song performed by Tony Bennett, three score tracks (all of which done by Bruce Roberts and Diana B), and three bonus songs from 1998's Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer: The Movie; another Rudolph project the company GoodTimes produced three years preceding this film.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;To those who are curious to relive this lump of coal in action, watch the film here: &lt;a href="https://archive.org/details/rcvrudolphnl10" rel="nofollow"&gt;Rudolph The Red-Nosed Reindeer And The Island Of Misfit Toys : GoodTimes Entertainment, Golden Books Family Entertainment, Classic Media, Dreamworks Classics, NBCUniversal, Tundra Productions Inc. : Free Download, Borrow, and Streaming : Internet Archive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Original film and music © GoodTimes Entertainment / Golden Books Family Entertainment / Tundra Productions Inc. / Chalkboard Music Inc. / St. Nicholas Music Inc. (ASCAP)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Copyright Disclaimer Under Section 107 of the Copyright Act 1976, allowance is made for "fair use" for purposes such as criticism, comment, news reporting, teaching, scholarship, and research. Fair use is a use permitted by copyright statute that might otherwise be infringing. Non-profit, educational or personal use tips the balance in favor of fair use.&lt;/div&gt;</description>
  <language>eng</language>
  <licenseurl>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</licenseurl>
  <scanner>Internet Archive HTML5 Uploader 1.6.4</scanner>
  <subject>Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer</subject>
  <subject>The Island of Misfit Toys</subject>
  <subject>Original Motion Picture Soundtrack</subject>
  <title>Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer &amp; The Island of Misfit Toys: Original Motion Picture Soundtrack</title>
  <uploader>ce_pro.co@hotmail.com</uploader>
  <publicdate>2020-12-09 17:53:14</publicdate>
  <addeddate>2020-12-09 17:53:14</addeddate>
  <curation>[curator]validator@archive.org[/curator][date]20201209175542[/date][comment]checked for malware[/comment]</curation>
  <year>2001</year>
  <collection>hifidelity</collection>
</metadata>
