<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <identifier>Cory_Doctorow_Podcast_305</identifier>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <collection>podcast_corydoctorow</collection>
  <collection>podcasts</collection>
  <creator>Cory Doctorow</creator>
  <date>2019-07-28</date>
  <description>
In my latest podcast, I read my essay &lt;a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2019/07/adblocking-how-about-nah" rel="nofollow"&gt;Adblocking: How About Nah?&lt;/a&gt;, published last week on EFF's Deeplinks; it's the latest installment in my series about "adversarial interoperability," and the role it has historically played in keeping tech open and competitive, and how that role is changing now that yesterday's scrappy startups have become today's bloated incumbents, determined to prevent anyone from disrupting them they way they disrupted tech in their early days.

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At the height of the pop-up wars, it seemed like there was no end in sight: the future of the Web would be one where humans adapted to pop-ups, then pop-ups found new, obnoxious ways to command humans' attention, which would wane, until pop-ups got even more obnoxious.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But that's not how it happened. Instead, browser vendors (beginning with Opera) started to ship on-by-default pop-up blockers. What's more, users—who hated pop-up ads—started to choose browsers that blocked pop-ups, marginalizing holdouts like Microsoft's Internet Explorer, until they, too, added pop-up blockers.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Chances are, those blockers are in your browser today. But here's a funny thing: if you turn them off, you won't see a million pop-up ads that have been lurking unseen for all these years.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Because once pop-up ads became invisible by default to an ever-larger swathe of Internet users, advertisers stopped demanding that publishers serve pop-up ads. The point of pop-ups was to get people's attention, but something that is never seen in the first place can't possibly do that.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
  <language>eng</language>
  <licenseurl>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</licenseurl>
  <scanner>Internet Archive HTML5 Uploader 1.6.4</scanner>
  <subject>cory doctorow</subject>
  <subject>podcasts</subject>
  <subject>competition</subject>
  <subject>adversarial interoperability</subject>
  <subject>decentralized web</subject>
  <subject>monopolism</subject>
  <subject>ads</subject>
  <subject>ad-tech</subject>
  <subject>browser wars</subject>
  <subject>eme</subject>
  <subject>w3c</subject>
  <subject>drm</subject>
  <subject>copyfight</subject>
  <title>Podcast: Adblocking: How About Nah?</title>
  <publicdate>2019-07-29 18:52:14</publicdate>
  <uploader>doctorow@craphound.com</uploader>
  <addeddate>2019-07-29 18:52:14</addeddate>
  <external_metadata_update>2019-09-25T10:48:11Z</external_metadata_update>
  <backup_location>ia906908_8</backup_location>
</metadata>
