<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <identifier>Cory_Doctorow_Podcast_273_fixed</identifier>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <collection>podcast_corydoctorow</collection>
  <creator>Cory Doctorow</creator>
  <date>2014-05-19</date>
  <description>Here's a reading of a my latest Guardian column, &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/may/14/firefox-closed-source-drm-video-browser-cory-doctorow" rel="nofollow"&gt;Firefox's adoption of closed-source DRM breaks my heart&lt;/a&gt;, a close analysis of the terrible news that Mozilla has opted to add closed source DRM to its flagship Firefox browser:

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The decision to produce systems that treat internet users as untrusted adversaries to be controlled by their computers was clearly taken out of a sense of desperation and inevitability.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It’s clear that Mozilla plans to do everything it can to mitigate the harms from its DRM strategy and to attempt to reverse the trend that brought it to this pass.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Like many of Mozilla’s longtime supporters, I hold it to a high standard. It is not a for-profit. It’s a social enterprise with a mission to empower and free its users.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I understand that Apple, Microsoft and Google are for-profit entities that have demonstrated repeatedly that their profitability trumps their customers’ rights, and I fault them for this. But it’s not unreasonable to hold mission-driven nonprofits to a higher standard than their commercial counterparts.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Mozilla says it’s doing everything it can to reduce the harm from what it sees as an inevitable decision. As a Mozilla supporter, contributor and user, I want it to do more.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Mastering by John Taylor Williams: wryneckstudio@gmail.com
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
John Taylor Williams is a audiovisual and multimedia producer based in Washington, DC and the co-host of the Living Proof Brew Cast. Hear him wax poetic over a pint or two of beer by visiting &lt;a href="http://livingproofbrewcast.com/" rel="nofollow"&gt;livingproofbrewcast.com&lt;/a&gt;. In his free time he makes "Beer Jewelry" and "Odd Musical Furniture." He often "meditates while reading cookbooks."  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
  <language>eng</language>
  <licenseurl>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licenseurl>
  <scanner>Internet Archive HTML5 Uploader 1.5.2</scanner>
  <subject>mozilla</subject>
  <subject>podcast</subject>
  <subject>drm</subject>
  <subject>w3c</subject>
  <subject>copyfight</subject>
  <subject>corydoctorow</subject>
  <title>Firefox's adoption of closed-source DRM breaks my heart</title>
  <publicdate>2014-05-20 04:59:09</publicdate>
  <uploader>doctorow@craphound.com</uploader>
  <addeddate>2014-05-20 04:59:09</addeddate>
  <boxid>OL100020112</boxid>
  <backup_location>ia905807_34</backup_location>
  <collection>podcasts</collection>
</metadata>
