<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <identifier>idwtbf</identifier>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <creator>Cory Doctorow</creator>
  <description>&lt;img src="//web.archive.org/web/2im_/http://media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/doctorow_jacket_press_draft6.pdf1.jpg" alt="doctorow_jacket_press_draft6.pdf1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here's Wil Wheaton reading chapter one ("Doctorow's First Law") of the independently produced audio edition of my nonfiction book &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1596436581/downandoutint-20" rel="nofollow"&gt;Information Doesn't Want to Be Free&lt;/a&gt; (published in 2014 by McSweeney's, with introductions by Amanda Palmer and Neil Gaiman).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The whole book is available as a &lt;a href="http://craphound.com/?p=5387" rel="nofollow"&gt;$15, DRM-free download&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Many thanks to Amanda Palmer and Dresden Dolls for permission to use the samples from Coin-Operated Boy in this recording.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here's Kirkus Reviews on &lt;i&gt;Information Doesn't Want to Be Free&lt;/i&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;     In his best-selling novel Ready Player One, Ernest 
Cline predicted that decades from now, Doctorow (Homeland, 2013, etc.) 
should share the presidency of the Internet with actor Wil Wheaton. 
Consider this manifesto to be Doctorow’s qualifications for the job. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
     The author provides a guide to the operation of the Internet that 
not only makes sense, but is also written for general readers. Using 
straightforward language and clear analogies, Doctorow breaks down the 
complex issues and tangled arguments surrounding technology, commerce, 
copyright, intellectual property, crowd funding, privacy and value—not 
to mention the tricky situation of becoming “Internet Famous.” Following
 a characteristically thoughtful introduction by novelist Neil Gaiman, 
rock star Amanda Palmer offers a blunt summary of today’s world: “We are
 a new generation of artists, makers, supporters, and consumers who 
believe that the old system through which we exchanged content and money
 is dead. Not dying: dead.” So the primary thesis of the book becomes a 
question of, where do we go from here? Identifying the Web’s 
constituents as creators, investors, intermediaries and audiences is 
just the first smart move. Doctorow also files his forthright, 
tactically savvy arguments under three “laws,” the most important of 
which has been well-broadcast: “Any time someone puts a lock on 
something that belongs to you and won’t give you the key, that lock 
isn’t there for your benefit.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
  <language>eng</language>
  <scanner>Internet Archive HTML5 Uploader 1.6.0</scanner>
  <subject>books</subject>
  <subject>drm</subject>
  <subject>copyfight</subject>
  <subject>audiobooks</subject>
  <subject>wil wheaton</subject>
  <subject>business models</subject>
  <subject>publishing</subject>
  <subject>cory doctorow</subject>
  <title>Cory Doctorow: Information Doesnt Wan't to Be Free, Chapter 1 (Read by Wil Wheaton)</title>
  <publicdate>2014-12-19 13:12:13</publicdate>
  <uploader>doctorow@craphound.com</uploader>
  <addeddate>2014-12-19 13:12:13</addeddate>
  <backup_location>ia905908_12</backup_location>
  <collection>podcast_corydoctorow</collection>
  <collection>podcasts</collection>
  <external_metadata_update>2019-04-05T09:12:53Z</external_metadata_update>
</metadata>
