<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <identifier>DoctorowAdisi</identifier>
  <title>Cory Doctorow's content used by ADISI</title>
  <creator>Cory Doctorow</creator>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <collection>cratediggers</collection>
  <collection>folksoundomy</collection>
  <description>&lt;b&gt;Update May 24, 2007&lt;/b&gt;: Today, ADISI chose to take down all the subpages of their &lt;a href="http://www.adisi.ch" rel="ugc nofollow"&gt;www.adisi.ch&lt;/a&gt; site (with the exception of www.adisi.ch/accessibilita, which they only host). This means that their "upgrade" of my translation of the excerpt from Cory Doctorow's talk at Olin College, which was the original motive for the creation of this item, is now off-line too. Nevertheless, I am keeping this item and the files contained in it, it case of future need. &lt;br /&gt; 
I was in charge of information and training at &lt;a href="http://www.adisi.ch" rel="ugc nofollow"&gt;ADISI&lt;/a&gt; Associazione di Diritto Informatico della Svizzera Italiana (Cyberlaw Association of Itallian-language Switzerland) from early 2002 to mid-October 2006. In this capacity, in April 2006, I asked Cory Doctorow's permission to use an extract of a talk he gave at Olin College on February 16, 2006 (see the post &lt;a href="http://www.craphound.com/?p=627" rel="ugc nofollow"&gt;Talk at Olin College&lt;/a&gt; on his blog, &lt;a href="http://www.craphound.com/" rel="ugc nofollow"&gt;craphound.com&lt;/a&gt;, from which the recording of the conference can be downloaded.He kindly consented.&lt;br /&gt;
The first idea was to use the extract in a broadcast of the &lt;a href="http://www.adisi.ch/tamtam/" rel="ugc nofollow"&gt;Tam Tam&lt;/a&gt; radio series ADISI was then producing for two local radios.So on April 28, 2006, I sent the text for the Italian dubbing to Giovanni Rengucci, chairman of ADISI and technical producer of Tam Tam, who was to record it. However, on May 9th, at the recording studio, he said the text was too complicated, and it would be better to publish it on a page of ADISI's site, with a link to the corresponding part of the original audio.&lt;br /&gt;
On May 15 2006, I sent ADISI the html page I had  made from the dubbing text and the audio extract. These were published as &lt;a href="http://www.adisi.ch/in-formazione/doctorow_drm.html" rel="ugc nofollow"&gt;Il Digital Rights Management ci riguarda tutti&lt;/a&gt; (web page) and &lt;a rel="ugc nofollow"&gt;adisi.ch/tamtam/mp3/2006/complete/tamtam_doctorow_ing.mp3&lt;/a&gt; (audio file).&lt;br /&gt;
Mid-October 2006, my collaboration with ADISI stopped.On November 30, 2006, ADISI &lt;a href="http://adisi.livejournal.com/64400.html" rel="ugc nofollow"&gt;announced on its blog&lt;/a&gt; a totally updated version of the main site, which then went off-line for corrections in early January 2007, except for a home page announcing that the site was being completely re-edited. In early April, other pages started reappearing, in an updated version - among which the page with the translation of the excerpt of Doctorow's talk, in &lt;a href="http://www.adisi.ch/nuova-divulgazione/nuova-documentazione/diritto-dautore-e--consumatori.html" rel="ugc nofollow"&gt;adisi.ch/nuova-divulgazione/nuova-documentazione/diritto-dautore-e--consumatori.html&lt;/a&gt;. But in this new page, which starts with "Written by ADISI's editorial board", followed by "By Cory Doctorow", the updating consists mainly in making the style very pompous, adding factual mistakes, and, bizarrely, changing "A un incontro dell'OMPI dove questa proposta veniva discussa, ho chiesto al rappresentante della Motion Picture Association of America come, secondo lui, sarebbe stata implementata nel mondo reale. Mi ha risposto..." (translation of "So when I asked the MPAA's representative at the WIPO hearings that I was at on this: "How do you expect this will play out in the real world?" He said....") into "Ad un incontro dell'OMPI, dove questa proposta veniva discussa, ADISI ha chiesto al rappresentante della Motion Picture Association of America, a quali conseguenze concrete, secondo lui, si sarebbe giunti. Ci rispose...", which means "During a meeting at WIPO, ADISI asked the MPAA's representative what, according to him, would be the concrete consquences. He answered us..."&lt;br /&gt;
Hence my decision to put here the material evidence of what happened. Even if I don't collaborate with ADISI anymore, and hence have nothing to do with their doctoring Doctorow's content, I have a moral responsibility for having asked his permission to publish it on ADISI's site in the first place. I can only say that when I did, I believed that ADISI's chairman's discourses about the need for furthering awareness of legal issues and a responsible use of the internet was sincere. But stupidity is no excuse. &lt;br /&gt;
I chose the dedication to the public domain license, because it is the one Cory Doctorow chose for the transcript of the above mentioned talk in &lt;a href="http://almansi.wikispaces.com/Doctorow+DRM+talk" rel="ugc nofollow"&gt;Doctorow DRM talk&lt;/a&gt;. The files that don't show on this page can be accessed from the FTP link on the left&lt;br /&gt;
Claude Almansi</description>
  <subject>ADISI; Rengucci; Doctorow; DRM; Digital Rights Management; Tam Tam;</subject>
  <licenseurl>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/publicdomain/</licenseurl>
  <publicdate>2007-05-20 20:45:23</publicdate>
  <addeddate>2007-05-20 20:44:01</addeddate>
  <uploader>claude.almansi@bluewin.ch</uploader>
  <updater>Claude Almansi</updater>
  <updater>Claude Almansi</updater>
  <updater>Claude Almansi</updater>
  <updater>Claude Almansi</updater>
  <updatedate>2007-05-20 21:18:38</updatedate>
  <updatedate>2007-05-22 01:08:56</updatedate>
  <updatedate>2007-05-23 22:13:59</updatedate>
  <updatedate>2007-05-24 15:16:02</updatedate>
  <contributor>Claude Almansi</contributor>
  <publisher>Claude Almansi</publisher>
  <language>Italian and English</language>
  <coverage>US and Switzerland</coverage>
  <identifier-access>http://www.archive.org/details/DoctorowAdisi</identifier-access>
  <identifier-ark>ark:/13960/t93778881</identifier-ark>
  <curation>[curator]validator@archive.org[/curator][date]20140405135535[/date][comment]checked for malware[/comment]</curation>
  <backup_location>ia903601_0</backup_location>
  <external_metadata_update>2019-03-29T07:59:01Z</external_metadata_update>
</metadata>
