<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <identifier>Cory_Doctorow_Podcast_232</identifier>
  <uploader>doctorow@craphound.com</uploader>
  <addeddate>2012-07-09 13:02:58</addeddate>
  <mediatype>audio</mediatype>
  <collection>podcast_corydoctorow</collection>
  <collection>podcasts</collection>
  <title>Music: The Internet's Original Sin</title>
  <description>Here's a podcast of my recent &lt;em&gt;Locus&lt;/em&gt; column, &lt;a href="http://www.locusmag.com/Perspectives/2012/07/cory-doctorow-music-the-internets-original-sin/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Music: The Internet's Original Sin&lt;/a&gt;:

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Let's start with music's age. Movies are still in their infancy. Books are in their middle age. Stories themselves are ancient. But music is primal. Books may predate commerce, but music predates language. Our relationship with music, and our social contracts around it, are woven into many other parts of our culture, parts that are considered more important than mere laws or businesses. The idea that music is something that you hear and then sing may even be inherent to our biology. I know that when I hear a catchy tune, I find myself humming it or singing it, and it takes a serious effort of will to stop myself. It doesn't really matter what the law says about whether I am ''authorized'' to ''perform'' a song. Once it's in my head, I'm singing it, and often singing it with my friends. If my friends and I sing together by means of video-sharing on YouTube, well, you're going to have a hard time convincing us that this is somehow wrong.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Music is also contingent. The part of a song that is ''musical'' is totally up for grabs, and changes from society to society and age to age. The European tradition has tended to elevate melody, so we think of ''writing a song'' as ''writing the melody.'' Afro-Caribbean traditions stress rhythms, especially complex polyrhythms. To grossly oversimplify, a traditional European song with a different beat (but the same melody) can still be the same song. A traditional Afro-Caribbean song with a different melody (but the same rhythm) can still be the same song. The law of music – written by Europeans and people of European descent – recognizes strong claims to authorship for the melodist, but not the drummer. Conveniently (for businesses run in large part by Europeans and people of European descent), this has meant that the part of the music that Europeans value can't be legally sampled or re-used without permission, but the part of the music characteristic of Afro-Caribbean performers can be treated as mere infrastructure by ''white'' acts. To be more blunt: the Beatles can take black American music's rock-n-roll rhythms without permission, but DJ Danger Mouse can't take the Beatles' melodies from the White Album to make the illegal hiphop classic The Grey Album.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Mastering by John Taylor Williams: wryneckstudio@gmail.com
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
John Taylor Williams is a audiovisual and multimedia producer based in Washington, DC and the co-host of the Living Proof Brew Cast. Hear him wax poetic over a pint or two of beer by visiting &lt;a href="http://livingproofbrewcast.com/" rel="nofollow"&gt;livingproofbrewcast.com&lt;/a&gt;. In his free time he makes "Beer Jewelry" and "Odd Musical Furniture." He often "meditates while reading cookbooks."&lt;/p&gt;</description>
  <subject>corydoctorow;podcast;copyfight;policy;law;music</subject>
  <creator>Cory Doctorow</creator>
  <licenseurl>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licenseurl>
  <publicdate>2012-07-09 13:03:04</publicdate>
  <boxid>OL100020112</boxid>
  <backup_location>ia903806_23</backup_location>
  <external_metadata_update>2019-03-30T18:03:00Z</external_metadata_update>
  <collection>podcasts_miscellaneous</collection>
  <collection_added>podcasts_miscellaneous</collection_added>
</metadata>
